{"1": {"question": "What does the nocturne's association with night relate to?", "correct": "Being performed in the evenings", "incorrect": ["Theme of the idea of night", "Serving royalty in the ranks of knights", "Being a part of a set of works with other themes such as day"]}, "2": {"question": "When did pieces titled notturno first appear?", "correct": "18th century", "incorrect": ["17th century", "19th century", "20th century"]}, "3": {"question": "Bel Canto, an influence on Chopin, translates to 'beautiful singing'. What did this style place an emphasis on?", "correct": "The beauty of the singing voice and its agility and expressiveness", "incorrect": ["The beauty of the singing voice and its regality and power", "The expressiveness of the singing voice and how it can have a loud and full sound", "The annoying opera sound"]}, "4": {"question": "What form is Chopin's Nocturne no.1 in?", "correct": "Ternary", "incorrect": ["Binary", "Sonata", "Consent"]}, "5": {"question": "Which of the following was a distinctive feature of Chopin's notation of the accompaniment pattern?", "correct": "Complex arrangement of stems", "incorrect": ["Basso continuo", "Rhythmic repetition", "Consecutive fifths and octaves"]}, "6": {"question": "What does the tempo designation in nocturne no.1 (cantabile) mean?", "correct": "'In a singing style'", "incorrect": ["'Like song'", "'Smooth and silky'", "'Cantaloupe' aka rockmelon"]}, "7": {"question": "What does 'semplice e tranquillo' mean?", "correct": "Unaffected and calm", "incorrect": ["Simple and tranquil", "Unaffected and tranquil", "Simple and smooth"]}, "8": {"question": "Who are Chopin's Op. 15 set of nocturnes dedicated to?", "correct": "Ferdinand Hiller", "incorrect": ["Franz Liszt", "Heinrich Heine", "Hector Berlioz"]}, "9": {"question": "The term for the extended embellishment that is seen in nocturne no.2 is fioritura, meaning what?", "correct": "Flowering", "incorrect": ["Finishing", "Grand and forte (loud)", "Fortified"]}, "10": {"question": "When were Chopin's No.15 nocturnes published?", "correct": "1834", "incorrect": ["1843", "1934", "1943"]}, "11": {"question": "Which of the following was NOT a contemporary of Chopin?", "correct": "Franz Schubert", "incorrect": ["Robert Schumann", "Felix Mendelssohn", "Cesar Franck"]}, "12": {"question": "What nationality was Chopin?", "correct": "Polish", "incorrect": ["French", "Austrian", "Mongolian"]}, "13": {"question": "What was Chopin's primary instrument?", "correct": "Piano", "incorrect": ["Harpsichord", "Flute", "Violin"]}, "14": {"question": "Which of the three nocturnes is the most elaborate, featuring a highly ornamental line for the right hand?", "correct": "No. 2", "incorrect": ["No. 1", "No. 3", "No. 4"]}, "15": {"question": "All of Chopin's compositions include which instrument?", "correct": "Piano", "incorrect": ["Harpsichord", "Flute", "Voice"]}, "16": {"question": "In the last 18 years of his life, Chopin gave only 30 public performances, preferring which setting?", "correct": "The salon", "incorrect": ["The chambers", "The concert hall", "The cathedral"]}, "17": {"question": "What nationality was Chopin's father?", "correct": "French", "incorrect": ["Polish", "German", "Warsawian", "Austro-Hungarian"]}, "18": {"question": "Which instrumental genre did Chopin create?", "correct": "The instrumental ballade", "incorrect": ["The polonaise", "The mazurka", "Music with nationalism"]}, "19": {"question": "What instrument did Chopin begin lessons on in 1823?", "correct": "Organ", "incorrect": ["Piano", "Violin", "Flute"]}, "20": {"question": "What did Chopin study at the Warsaw Conservatory?", "correct": "Music theory, figured bass, and composition", "incorrect": ["Music theory, figured bass, and word painting", "Music theory, composition, and performance", "Music theory, performance, and composition"]}, "21": {"question": "Who composed the Nocturne No 5 in Bb major, H 37?", "correct": "John Field", "incorrect": ["Robert Schumann", "Franz Schubert", "Frederic Chopin"]}, "22": {"question": "To what extent was the Italian opera in the 1830s an influence on Chopin?", "correct": "Striking", "incorrect": ["Great", "Moderate", "Little"]}, "23": {"question": "What movement is the first movement of Schumann's Piano Quintet in?", "correct": "Sonata form", "incorrect": ["Rondo form", "Theme and variations", "Strophic"]}, "24": {"question": "What key is Schumann's Piano Quintet in?", "correct": "Eb major", "incorrect": ["Ab major", "Bb major", "Fb major"]}, "25": {"question": "Schumann had not (with one juvenile exception) composed chamber music until what year?", "correct": "1842", "incorrect": ["1840", "1832", "1845"]}, "26": {"question": "What is an obbligato accompaniment?", "correct": "An elaborate and indispensable accompaniment", "incorrect": ["A simple and essential accompaniment", "The melody played in the accompaniment", "An accompaniment obliged to play an accompanying part"]}, "27": {"question": "Prior to 1840, Schumann had only written music for what instrument?", "correct": "Piano", "incorrect": ["Organ", "Violin", "Voice"]}, "28": {"question": "What is Schumann's Liederjahr?", "correct": "Year of songs", "incorrect": ["Knee-lengths leather breeches", "Setting poetry to classical music", "Lid and jar"]}, "29": {"question": "Where and when did Schumann's Piano Quintet Op. 44 premiere?", "correct": "Concert hall of the Leipzig Gewandhaus in 1843", "incorrect": ["Concert hall of the Leipzig Gewandhaus in 1842", "Concert hall of the Leipzig Kupfersaal in 1843", "Concert hall of the Leipzig Kupfersaal in 1842"]}, "30": {"question": "Why is Schumann's Piano Quintet Op. 44 considered a watershed work?", "correct": "It made the Piano and string quartet format the favoured one for Piano quintets", "incorrect": ["It made the Piano and string quartets the disliked format for Piano quintets", "It made the Piano quintet the favoured format", "Because of the flooding in regional NSW"]}, "31": {"question": "Who played piano on Schumann's Piano Quintet Op. 44 in the premiere show?", "correct": "His wife, Clara Schumann", "incorrect": ["His father, August Schumann", "His mother, Johanna Christine Schnabel", "His son, Felix Schumann"]}, "32": {"question": "What did Schumann compose in addition to the Quintet in 1842?", "correct": "Three string quartets, a Piano quartet and a set of Phantasiestücke", "incorrect": ["Four string quartets, a Piano quintet and a set of Phantasiestücke", "Three string quartets, a Piano quartet and a set of Phantasiestücke", "Three string quartets, two Piano quintets and a set of Phantasiestücke"]}, "33": {"question": "What did Schumann do in his Liederjahr?", "correct": "Turned his attention almost entirely to writing German songs, or Lieder", "incorrect": ["Reflected on all his life choices", "Turned his attention to writing poetry", "Ate some marmalade"]}, "34": {"question": "What is one feature of Schumann's Quintet that distinguishes it from Classical (e.g. Mozart and Haydn) Sonata form?", "correct": "Tendency towards a continuous texture in which many of the ends of thematic units and cadence points elide with the next thematic unit", "incorrect": ["Tendency to get distracted", "Tendency towards a dense texture in which many of the ends of thematic units end in cadences that have dense voicings", "An extensive use of ornamentation and expressive techniques"]}, "35": {"question": "What key is the first subordinate theme in the exposition of Schumann's Quintet in? ", "correct": "The dominant Bb major", "incorrect": ["The dominant Eb major", "The relative major Bb major", "Eb minor"]}, "36": {"question": "How long is the main theme in Schumann's Quintet?", "correct": "8 bars", "incorrect": ["16 bars", "12 bars", "4 bars"]}, "37": {"question": "Schumann's Piano Quintet Op. 44 was dedicated to _______ and remained a staple in her repertoire throughout her long pianistic career.", "correct": "Clara Schumann", "incorrect": ["Johanna Christine Schnabel", "Joan Samantha Bach", "Maria Schumann"]}, "38": {"question": "Which section is the least predictable part of the First movement of Schumann's Piano Quintet Op. 44?", "correct": "Development", "incorrect": ["Exposition", "Recapitulation", "Coda"]}, "39": {"question": "Which instrument is featured in a soloistic role in the development of the first movement of Schumann's Piano Quintet Op.44?", "correct": "Piano", "incorrect": ["Violin", "Viola", "Cello"]}, "40": {"question": "What is the role of the strings section in the development of the first movement of Schumann's Piano Quintet Op.44?", "correct": "Accompaniment", "incorrect": ["Soloistic", "Melodic", "Chairman"]}, "41": {"question": "Which era is Robert Schumann from?", "correct": "Romantic period", "incorrect": ["Classical period", "Baroque period", "Contemporary period"]}, "42": {"question": "Who loved to write proper names such as Abegg, Asch and Bach in musical notation and then use them as themes in his works?", "correct": "Schumann", "incorrect": ["Schubert", "Handel", "Mendelssohn", "Rorschach"]}, "43": {"question": "When writing melodies in the minor, avoid the augmented interval between the sixth and seventh degrees of which minor scale?", "correct": "Harmonic", "incorrect": ["Melodic", "Natural", "Relative"]}, "44": {"question": "Who composed The Erl King?", "correct": "Schubert", "incorrect": ["Schumann", "Beethoven", "Mozart"]}, "45": {"question": "What is 'Tierce de Picardie'?", "correct": "Minor triad with a semitone raised third", "incorrect": ["Major triad with a semitone lowered third", "A French cake", "The first inversion of a triad which puts the bottom note as the third"]}, "46": {"question": "What should be the first action taken when approaching four-part vocal compositions?", "correct": "Complete the cadences", "incorrect": ["Add a bass", "Put chord indications for the whole thing", "Add inner parts"]}, "47": {"question": "What key should you set a poem with sad lyrics to?", "correct": "Minor", "incorrect": ["Major", "Wholetone", "E major"]}, "48": {"question": "Who built the first piano in 1709?", "correct": "Cristofori", "incorrect": ["Mozart", "Schröder", "Hermann Poll"]}, "49": {"question": "How did the piano of Mozart's time differ from the present?", "correct": "It had a thin tone and was only 5 octaves", "incorrect": ["Had a larger range", "Had an overwhelming sound with a higher dynamic capability", "It didn't come with cup holders"]}, "50": {"question": "What does the name pianoforte indicate?", "correct": "Its sound can be varied from soft to loud by the touch of the fingers", "incorrect": ["Its sound can be varied from soft to loud through telepathy", "A serious inability to be creative when naming an instrument", "That the moon landing was fake"]}, "51": {"question": "What does the nocturne's association with night relate to?", "correct": "Being performed in the evenings", "incorrect": ["Theme of the idea of night", "Serving royalty in the ranks of knights", "Being a part of a set of works with other themes such as day"]}, "52": {"question": "When did pieces titled notturno first appear?", "correct": "18th century", "incorrect": ["17th century", "19th century", "20th century"]}, "53": {"question": "What is sympathetic resonance?", "correct": "Harmonic phenomenon where a passive string responds to external vibrations to which it has harmonic likeness", "incorrect": ["Harmonic phenomenon where an active string responds to external vibrations to which it has harmonic likeness", "Harmonic phenomenon where a passive string responds to internal vibrations to which it has harmonic dissonance", "Harmonic phenomenon where a passive string responds to external vibrations to which it has harmonic dissonance"]}, "54": {"question": "Who created the notion that the piano could be a singing instrument?", "correct": "John Field", "incorrect": ["Mozart", "Henry Purcell", "A lunatic"]}, "55": {"question": "Bel Canto, an influence on Chopin, translates to 'beautiful singing'. What did this style place an emphasis on?", "correct": "The beauty of the singing voice and its agility and expressiveness", "incorrect": ["The beauty of the singing voice and its regality and power", "The expressiveness of the singing voice and how it can have a loud and full sound", "The annoying opera sound"]}, "56": {"question": "What form is Chopin's Nocturne no.1 in?", "correct": "Ternary", "incorrect": ["Binary", "Sonata", "Consent"]}, "57": {"question": "Which of the following was a distinctive feature of Chopin's notation of the accompaniment pattern?", "correct": "Complex arrangement of stems", "incorrect": ["Basso continuo", "Rhythmic repetition", "Consecutive fifths and octaves"]}, "58": {"question": "What does the tempo designation in nocturne no.1 (cantabile) mean?", "correct": "In a singing style'", "incorrect": ["Like song'", "Smooth and silky'", "Cantaloupe' aka rockmelon"]}, "59": {"question": "What does 'semplice e tranquillo' mean?", "correct": "Unaffected and calm", "incorrect": ["Simple and tranquil", "Unaffected and tranquil", "Simple and smooth"]}, "60": {"question": "What interval should be avoided in minor melodies?", "correct": "The augmented interval between the sixth and seventh degrees of the harmonic minor scale", "incorrect": ["The diminished interval between the fifth and the sixth degrees of the harmonic minor scale", "The augmented interval between the sixth and seventh degrees of the melodic minor scale", "The wholetone interval"]}, "61": {"question": "Who composed the Unfinished Symphony?", "correct": "Franz Schubert", "incorrect": ["JS Bach", "CP Bach", "WA Mozart"]}, "62": {"question": "Which composer was often referred to as 'the pianist's composer' and 'the poet of the piano'?", "correct": "Chopin", "incorrect": ["Liszt", "Brahms", "Mendelssohn"]}, "63": {"question": "What are the four most common woodwind instruments found in orchestral and chamber music?", "correct": "Flute, oboe, clarinet, bassoon", "incorrect": ["Flute, oboe, saxophone, bassoon", "Oboe, clarinet, flute, violin", "Piccolo, flute, clarinet, oboe"]}, "64": {"question": "What shape is bore of the clarinet?", "correct": "Cylindrical", "incorrect": ["Conical ", "Long", "Straight"]}, "65": {"question": "Who developed the Boehm system of clarinet keywork?", "correct": "Hyacinthe Klosé and Auguste Buffet jeune", "incorrect": ["Theobald Boehm", "Richard Rodgers and Lorenz Hart", "John"]}, "66": {"question": "What does fagotto (on an orchestral score) translate to?", "correct": "Bassoon", "incorrect": ["Oboe", "Clarinet", "Flute"]}, "67": {"question": "What instrument is the bass version of the double reed family?", "correct": "Bassoon", "incorrect": ["Oboe", "Clarinet", "Cor Anglais"]}, "68": {"question": "How do you saxophone (worth 10 marks)", "correct": "Blow air", "incorrect": ["Yes", "Mendelssohn", "Cheese"]}, "69": {"question": "What is imitation?", "correct": "A polyphonic musical texture in which a melodic idea is freely or strictly echoed by successive voices", "incorrect": ["A succession of two distinct phrases usually written in different parts of the music, where the second phrase is heard as a direct commentary on or in response to the first", "Signifies a note of shortened duration, separated from the note that may follow by silence", "Rude"]}, "70": {"question": "What is a coloratura soprano?", "correct": "A type of operatic voice that specialises in music distinguished by agile runs, leaps, and trills", "incorrect": ["Classical female singing voice whose vocal range lies between the soprano and contralto voice types", "Classical male singing voice whose vocal range lies between the countertenor and baritone voice types", "A type of operatic voice that has a warm quality with a bright, full timbre that can be heard over an orchestra"]}, "71": {"question": "Who are Chopin's Op. 15 set of nocturnes dedicated to?", "correct": "Ferdinand Hiller", "incorrect": ["Franz Liszt", "Heinrich Heine", "Hector Berlioz"]}, "72": {"question": "The term for the extended embellishment that is seen in nocturne no.2 is fioritura, meaning what?", "correct": "Flowering", "incorrect": ["Finishing", "Grand and forte (loud)", "Fortified"]}, "73": {"question": "When were Chopin's No.15 nocturnes published?", "correct": "1834", "incorrect": ["1843", "1934", "1943"]}, "74": {"question": "Who excelled at writing long-breathed, highly expressive and elaborate vocal lines which were typically supported by simple, slow moving accompaniment patterns?", "correct": "Vincenzo Bellini", "incorrect": ["Gaetano Donizetti", "Gioachino Rossini", "Belissimo"]}, "75": {"question": "What nationality was Claude Debussy?", "correct": "French", "incorrect": ["British", "German", "Austrian"]}, "76": {"question": "Which of the following was NOT a contemporary of Chopin?", "correct": "Franz Schubert", "incorrect": ["Robert Schumann", "Felix Mendelssohn", "Cesar Franck"]}, "77": {"question": "What nationality was Chopin?", "correct": "Polish", "incorrect": ["French", "Austrian", "Mongolian"]}, "78": {"question": "What was Chopin's primary instrument?", "correct": "Piano", "incorrect": ["Harpsichord", "Flute", "Violin"]}, "79": {"question": "Who founded the National Society of Music in 1871 in France?", "correct": "Saint Saens", "incorrect": ["Debussy", "Faure", "Ravel"]}, "80": {"question": "What interval does a clarinet overblow?", "correct": "A twelfth", "incorrect": ["An octave", "A fifth", "A tenth"]}, "81": {"question": "Which of the 4 primary Orchestral Woodwind instruments overblow an octave?", "correct": "Oboe, Bassoon, Flute", "incorrect": ["Oboe, Clarinet, Bassoon", "Clarinet, Bassoon, Flute", "Basoon, Oboe, Clarinet"]}, "82": {"question": "How should the sustain pedal be used in Romantic piano music?", "correct": "Subtly", "incorrect": ["Overly", "Not", "Mis-"]}, "83": {"question": "Which of the three nocturnes is the most elaborate, featuring a highly ornamental line for the right hand?", "correct": "No. 2", "incorrect": ["No. 1", "No. 3", "No. 4", "No. π"]}, "84": {"question": "What does abridged mean?", "correct": "Shortened", "incorrect": ["Extended", "Augmented", "Connected", "The middle section is in the key of A"]}, "85": {"question": "Integral of 2x?", "correct": "x^2 + C", "incorrect": ["2x^2", "x^2", "(x^2)/2", "2"]}, "86": {"question": "What is a pedal point?", "correct": "A note that is held through changing harmonies and is often in the bass", "incorrect": ["A note that moves whilst the harmonies are held and is often in the bass", "A note that is held and is often in the melody", "None of the above"]}, "87": {"question": "All of Chopin's compositions include which instrument?", "correct": "Piano", "incorrect": ["Harpsichord", "Flute", "Voice"]}, "88": {"question": "In the last 18 years of his life, Chopin gave only 30 public performances, preferring which setting?", "correct": "The salon", "incorrect": ["The chambers", "The concert hall", "The cathedral"]}, "89": {"question": "What nationality was Chopin's father?", "correct": "French", "incorrect": ["Polish", "German", "Warsawian", "Austro-Hungarian"]}, "90": {"question": "Which instrumental genre did Chopin create?", "correct": "The instrumental ballade", "incorrect": ["The polonaise", "The mazurka", "Music with nationalism"]}, "91": {"question": "What instrument did Chopin begin lessons on in 1823?", "correct": "Organ", "incorrect": ["Piano", "Violin", "Flute"]}, "92": {"question": "What did Chopin study at the Warsaw Conservatory?", "correct": "Music theory, figured bass, and composition", "incorrect": ["Music theory, figured bass, and word painting", "Music theory, composition, and performance", "Music theory, performance, and composition"]}, "93": {"question": "What is the purpose of 'half-pedalling'?", "correct": "Allows low notes to retain a presence without blurring higher stuff", "incorrect": ["Allows low notes to retain a presence whilst blurring higher stuff", "Allows high notes to retain a presence without blurring lower accompaniment", "To have a semi-blurred sound"]}, "94": {"question": "What movement is the first movement of Schumann's Piano Quintet in?", "correct": "Sonata form", "incorrect": ["Rondo form", "Theme and variations", "Strophic"]}, "95": {"question": "What key is Schumann's Piano Quintet (mvt 1) in?", "correct": "Eb major", "incorrect": ["Ab major", "Bb major", "Fb major"]}, "96": {"question": "Schumann had not (with one juvenile exception) composed chamber music until what year?", "correct": "1842", "incorrect": ["1840", "1832", "1845"]}, "97": {"question": "What is an obbligato accompaniment?", "correct": "An elaborate and indispensable accompaniment", "incorrect": ["A simple and essential accompaniment", "The melody played in the accompaniment", "An accompaniment obliged to play an accompanying part"]}, "98": {"question": "As the piano developed technologically, composers of chamber music increasingly turned to combinations involving larger groups of what?", "correct": "Strings", "incorrect": ["Percussion", "Brass", "Orchestra"]}, "99": {"question": "Who composed the Piano Quintet in A major, D 667 ('Trout') in 1819?", "correct": "Schubert", "incorrect": ["Schumann", "Chopin", "Mendelssohn"]}, "100": {"question": "Earlier forms of the piano quintet usually involved what instruments?", "correct": "Piano, Violin, Viola, Cello, and Double Bass", "incorrect": ["Piano, two Violins, Viola, and Cello", "Piano, Violin, two Violas, and a Cello", "Two Violins, Viola, Cello, and Double Bass"]}, "101": {"question": "Prior to 1840, Schumann had only written music for what instrument?", "correct": "Piano", "incorrect": ["Organ", "Violin", "Voice"]}, "102": {"question": "What does Phantasiestücke translate to?", "correct": "Fantasy pieces", "incorrect": ["Fantasy stuck", "Improvised pieces", "Abstract pieces"]}, "103": {"question": "Sonata form consists of which three movements?", "correct": "Exposition, development, recapitulation", "incorrect": ["Chorus, bridge, coda", "Exposition, development, exposition (ABA)", "Theme, variation, variation", "Tectonic, bowel, migratory"]}, "104": {"question": "What is typically found between the main and subordinate themes in the exposition of a piece in Sonata form?", "correct": "A transition", "incorrect": ["A bridge", "A development", "Peanut butter"]}, "105": {"question": "In which movement of Sonata form is the motivic material 'worked over'?", "correct": "Development", "incorrect": ["Exposition", "Recapitulation", "Bridge"]}, "106": {"question": "When did chamber music for piano and strings first appear?", "correct": "Mid-eighteenth century", "incorrect": ["Early-nineteenth century", "Late-eighteenth century", "Early-eighteenth century"]}, "107": {"question": "What is the instrumentation of a string quartet?", "correct": "Two Violins, Viola and Cello", "incorrect": ["Violin, Viola, Cello and Double Bass", "Piano, Violin, Viola, Cello", "Piano, two Violins, Cello"]}, "108": {"question": "What is Schumann's Liederjahr?", "correct": "Year of songs", "incorrect": ["Knee-lengths leather breeches", "Setting poetry to classical music", "Lid and jar"]}, "109": {"question": "Where and when did Schumann's Piano Quintet Op. 44 premiere?", "correct": "Concert hall of the Leipzig Gewandhaus in 1843", "incorrect": ["Concert hall of the Leipzig Gewandhaus in 1842", "Concert hall of the Leipzig Kupfersaal in 1843", "Concert hall of the Leipzig Kupfersaal in 1842"]}, "110": {"question": "Why is Schumann's Piano Quintet Op. 44 considered a watershed work?", "correct": "It made the Piano and string quartet format the favoured one for Piano quintets", "incorrect": ["It made the Piano and string quartets the disliked format for Piano quintets", "It made the Piano quintet the favoured format", "Because of the flooding in regional NSW"]}, "111": {"question": "Who played piano on Schumann's Piano Quintet Op. 44 in the premiere show?", "correct": "His wife, Clara Schumann", "incorrect": ["His father, August Schumann", "His mother, Johanna Christine Schnabel", "His son, Felix Schumann", "His wife, August Schumann", "His father, Clara Schumann"]}, "112": {"question": "Who composed the Nocturne No 5 in Bb major, H 37?", "correct": "John Field", "incorrect": ["Robert Schumann", "Franz Schubert", "Frederic Chopin"]}, "113": {"question": "To what extent was the Italian opera in the 1830s an influence on Chopin?", "correct": "Striking", "incorrect": ["Great", "Moderate", "Little"]}, "114": {"question": "What did Schumann compose in addition to the Quintet in 1842?", "correct": "Three string quartets, a piano quartet and a set of Phantasiestücke", "incorrect": ["Four string quartets, a piano quintet and a set of Phantasiestücke", "Three string quartets, a piano quartet and a set of Phantasiestücke", "Three string quartets, two piano quintets and a set of Phantasiestücke"]}, "115": {"question": "What did Schumann do in his Liederjahr?", "correct": "Turned his attention almost entirely to writing German songs, or Lieder", "incorrect": ["Reflected on all his life choices", "Turned his attention to writing poetry", "Ate some marmalade", "Played xbox"]}, "116": {"question": "What is one feature of Schumann's Quintet that distinguishes it from Classical (e.g. Mozart and Haydn) Sonata form?", "correct": "Tendency towards a continuous texture in which many of the ends of thematic units and cadence points elide with the next thematic unit", "incorrect": ["Tendency to get distracted", "Tendency towards a dense texture in which many of the ends of thematic units end in cadences that have dense voicings", "An extensive use of ornamentation and expressive techniques"]}, "117": {"question": "What key is the first subordinate theme in the exposition of Schumann's Quintet in? ", "correct": "The dominant Bb major", "incorrect": ["The dominant Eb major", "The relative major Bb major", "Eb minor"]}, "118": {"question": "How long is the main theme in Schumann's Quintet?", "correct": "8 bars", "incorrect": ["16 bars", "12 bars", "4 bars"]}, "119": {"question": "What is an elided cadence?", "correct": "Final chord of the cadence is the first chord of the next phrase", "incorrect": ["First chord of the cadence is the final chord of the last phrase", "Final chord of the cadence is the final chord of the next phrase", "First chord of the cadence is the first chord of the next phrase"]}, "120": {"question": "How do you elide a themative unit?", "correct": "Sharing a note as the last note of the first unit and the first note of the next", "incorrect": ["Sharing a note as the first note of the last unit and first note of the first", "Sharing a note as the last note of the first unit and the last note of a cadence", "Final chord of the cadence is the first chord of the next phrase"]}, "121": {"question": "What is the capital of Zimbabwe?", "correct": "Harare", "incorrect": ["Cape Town", "Johannesburg", "Mozart", "Z", "Robert Mugabe"]}, "122": {"question": "Schumann's Piano Quintet Op. 44 was dedicated to _______ and remained a staple in her repertoire throughout her long pianistic career.", "correct": "Clara Schumann", "incorrect": ["Johanna Christine Schnabel", "Joan Samantha Bach", "Maria Schumann"]}, "123": {"question": "Which section is the least predictable part of the First movement of Schumann's Piano Quintet Op. 44?", "correct": "Development", "incorrect": ["Exposition", "Recapitulation", "Coda"]}, "124": {"question": "Many of the standard theme structures of the _________ style are not as readily identifiable in this work.", "correct": "Classical", "incorrect": ["Baroque", "Romantic", "Free"]}, "125": {"question": "Which instrument is featured in a soloistic role in the development of the first movement of Schumann's Piano Quintet Op.44?", "correct": "Piano", "incorrect": ["Violin", "Viola", "Cello"]}, "126": {"question": "What is the role of the strings section in the development of the first movement of Schumann's Piano Quintet Op.44?", "correct": "Accompaniment", "incorrect": ["Soloistic", "Melodic", "Chairman", "Percussion"]}, "127": {"question": "How do thicker strings change the sound on a piano?", "correct": "They make the sound richer", "incorrect": ["They make the sound thinner", "They don't change the sound of a piano", "They make the sound thicker"]}, "128": {"question": "Which era is Robert Schumann from?", "correct": "Romantic period", "incorrect": ["Classical period", "Baroque period", "Contemporary period"]}, "129": {"question": "Who wrote Kinderszenen (Scenes from childhood)?", "correct": "Schumann", "incorrect": ["Schubert", "Handel", "Haydn"]}, "130": {"question": "Who loved to write proper names such as Abegg, Asch and Bach in musical notation and then use them as themes in his works?", "correct": "Schumann", "incorrect": ["Schubert", "Handel", "Mendelssohn"]}, "131": {"question": "Who composed Fantaisie-Impromptu?", "correct": "Chopin", "incorrect": ["Schumann", "Mendelssohn", "Brahms"]}, "132": {"question": "What is a basso ostinato?", "correct": "A form of ground bass in which a short bass pattern is repeated many times unchanged", "incorrect": ["An accompanying part that includes a bassline and harmonies, typically played on a keyboard instrument", "A continually repeated musical motif", "A bass part that never stops", "A deep sea fish with a mottled pattern on its scales"]}, "133": {"question": "Who invented the pianoforte?", "correct": "Bartolommeo Cristofori", "incorrect": ["Adolphe Sax", "Ferdinando de' Medici", "Leonardo da Vinci"]}, "134": {"question": "The Clavichord was the favourite instrumet of which famous composer?", "correct": "Bach", "incorrect": ["Mozart", "Beethoven", "Handel"]}, "135": {"question": "The harpsichord was a double what?", "correct": "Spinet", "incorrect": ["Clavichord", "Pianoforte", "Big mac"]}, "136": {"question": "Who composed Solfeggietto?", "correct": "C.P.E. Bach", "incorrect": ["Beethoven", "Mozart", "Haydn"]}, "137": {"question": "Who composed Rondo in B minor?", "correct": "C.P.E. Bach", "incorrect": ["Weber", "Mozart", "Schubert"]}, "138": {"question": "Who composed Variations in F minor?", "correct": "Haydn", "incorrect": ["Mozart", "Beethoven", "Mendelssohn"]}, "139": {"question": "Who composed Fantasia in C major (Capriccio)?", "correct": "Haydn", "incorrect": ["C.P.E. Bach", "Handel", "Liszt"]}, "140": {"question": "Who composed the Sonata in D for two pianos?", "correct": "Mozart", "incorrect": ["Haydn", "C.P.E. Bach", "Beethoven"]}, "141": {"question": "Who composed Invitation to the Waltz?", "correct": "Weber", "incorrect": ["Schubert", "Schumann", "Chopin"]}, "142": {"question": "Who composed Fantasia in C major (Wanderer)?", "correct": "Schubert", "incorrect": ["Weber", "Haydn", "Bach"]}, "143": {"question": "Who composed the Hungarian Rhapsodies?", "correct": "Liszt", "incorrect": ["C.P.E. Bach", "Chopin", "Schumann"]}, "144": {"question": "Who composed Mendelssohn's Characterstücke?", "correct": "Mendelssohn", "incorrect": ["Chopin", "Liszt", "You are so small brain"]}, "145": {"question": "Who composed the Variations and Fugue on Theme of Handel?", "correct": "Brahms", "incorrect": ["Haydn", "Handel", "Debussy"]}, "146": {"question": "Who composed the Rhapsody on a theme of Paganini?", "correct": "Rachmaninoff", "incorrect": ["Shostakovich", "Bartok", "Prokofiev"]}, "147": {"question": "Who composed Rhapsody in blue?", "correct": "Gershwin", "incorrect": ["De Falla", "Weber", "Schumann"]}, "148": {"question": "Who composed Sonatina Op. 13?", "correct": "Kabalevsky", "incorrect": ["Shostakovich", "Paganini", "Telemann"]}, "149": {"question": "Who composed Three Fantastic Dances?", "correct": "Shostakovich", "incorrect": ["Gershwin", "Rachmaninoff", "Putin"]}, "150": {"question": "Who composed Variations on a Theme by Paganini?", "correct": "Brahms", "incorrect": ["Paganini", "Ravel", "Rachmaninoff"]}, "151": {"question": "Who composed Polichinelle?", "correct": "Rachmaninoff", "incorrect": ["Ravel", "Chopin", "Brahms"]}, "152": {"question": "Who composed Tombeau de Couperin?", "correct": "Ravel", "incorrect": ["Chopin", "Schumann", "Mozart"]}, "153": {"question": "Who composed Gaspard de la nuit?", "correct": "Ravel", "incorrect": ["Chopin", "Brahms", "Schubert"]}, "154": {"question": "Who composed almost a thousand works including the best studies ever written?!?!?!?!?!? 😱😱😱", "correct": "Czerny", "incorrect": ["Liszt", "Ravel", "Schumann"]}, "155": {"question": "Who wrote over 30 chamber works and the spirits of him dwells in them, for they are full of his magic melody lines - they was the greatest melodic genius the world has ever known. They was also a master of harmony and their adventurous harmony is the most striking feature of his chamber works. He, like Beethoven, had a strong sense of tonality, and at times has some entrancing changes of key. He was especially fond of changing the mode from major to minor or vice versa on the same tonic and also liked an abrupt change to a key a major 3rd below the tonic. Some of the most wonderful and widely-loved chamber works in all of music were written by this great composer?", "correct": "Schubert", "incorrect": ["Jesus", "Liszt", "Haydn"]}, "156": {"question": "Who composed Piano Quintet Op. 34?", "correct": "Brahms", "incorrect": ["Schumann", "Schubert", "Haydn"]}, "157": {"question": "Who composed Emperor Quartet?", "correct": "Haydn", "incorrect": ["Bach", "Beethoven", "Handel"]}, "158": {"question": "Who composed Barcarolle in F# minor?", "correct": "Chopin", "incorrect": ["Ravel", "Schumann", "Schubert"]}, "159": {"question": "The name Ballades first came into Piano music with which composer?", "correct": "Chopin", "incorrect": ["Haydn", "Field", "Handel"]}, "160": {"question": "Which composer wrote almost only for the piano?", "correct": "Chopin", "incorrect": ["Schumann", "Mozart", "Bach"]}, "161": {"question": "Which word is derived from the traditional song of Venetian gondoliers?", "correct": "Barcarolle", "incorrect": ["Ballades", "Mazurkas", "Polonaises"]}, "162": {"question": "What time signature is Chopin's Barcarolle in?", "correct": "12/8", "incorrect": ["6/8", "3/8", "7/8"]}, "163": {"question": "What is an etude?", "correct": "A study or technical exercise", "incorrect": ["Lively, loosely structured piece that is often humourous in character", "Any piece of music that is sung", "An instrumental musical form introduced in the Baroque period"]}, "164": {"question": "Who composed the Revolutionary Etude?", "correct": "Chopin", "incorrect": ["Haydn", "Mozart", "Brahms"]}, "165": {"question": "What does Scherzo mean?", "correct": "Joke", "incorrect": ["Frenzy", "Sudden", "Song"]}, "166": {"question": "To Chopin the title '________' embraced a multiplicity of contrasting musical ideas with alternating episodes of explosive passion and lyrically serene melody.", "correct": "Scherzo", "incorrect": ["Sonata", "Polonaise", "Impromptu"]}, "167": {"question": "At what age did Chopin compose his first sonata?", "correct": "18", "incorrect": ["21", "44", "6"]}, "168": {"question": "What is a polonaise?", "correct": "One of the national dances of Poland", "incorrect": ["A burger sauce", "A Polish military song", "A piece played before another piece/play/ceremony"]}, "169": {"question": "Which composer had a lamed hand?", "correct": "Schumann", "incorrect": ["Chopin", "Mozart", "Beethoven"]}, "170": {"question": "Who composed the 'ABEGG' Theme and Variations?", "correct": "Schumann", "incorrect": ["Chopin", "Liszt", "Brahms"]}, "171": {"question": "How many sonatas did Schumann compose?", "correct": "3", "incorrect": ["4", "1", "2"]}, "172": {"question": "What is a novelette?", "correct": "A short piece of lyrical music, especially one for piano", "incorrect": ["A short piece of lyrical music, especially one for vocal", "A long piece of lyrical music, especially one for piano", "A long piece of lyrical music, especially one for vocal"]}, "173": {"question": "What does Davidsbündlertänze translate to?", "correct": "Dances of the League of David", "incorrect": ["A group of eighteen pieces for piano", "Dances of David", "It's not a real word"]}, "174": {"question": "Translate Études Symphoniques", "correct": "Symphonic studies", "incorrect": ["Symphonic etudes", "Studies Symphoniques", "I refuse"]}, "175": {"question": "What does Faschingsschwank aus Wien translate to?", "correct": "Carnival jest from Vienna", "incorrect": ["Carnival sausages from Vienna", "Fashion from Vienna", "State government of Vienna"]}, "176": {"question": "Why is Schumann referred to as the founder of the Romantic Period in Music?", "correct": "His creative career coincided with the flowering of Romanticism in paining and literature", "incorrect": ["He ushered in a new style of playing music with elements of the Romantic style", "He possessed the rare gifts of the power of expression - from the humourous element to teh expression of a deep and subtle emotion", "In his music is a fresh, youthful note with heaven-soaring melodies, clashing harmonies and rushing rhythms"]}, "177": {"question": "Who devised the practice of placing the thumb under in scale passages?", "correct": "C.P.E. Bach", "incorrect": ["Mozart", "Beethoven", "Couperin"]}, "178": {"question": "What are Kinderszenen?", "correct": "Scenes from childhood", "incorrect": ["A type of chocolate", "Kindergarten", "Childlike songs"]}, "179": {"question": "What are Waldszenen?", "correct": "Woodland Scenes", "incorrect": ["Waltz songs", "Waltz Scenes", "Woodland songs"]}, "180": {"question": "What are Papillons?", "correct": "Butterflies", "incorrect": ["Papers", "Pepe", "Butter fingers"]}, "181": {"question": "What are Schumann's Kreisleriana?", "correct": "A set of eight fantasy pieces dedicated to Chopin", "incorrect": ["A set of six fantasy pieces dedicated to Chopin", "His signature cookies", "A set of eight fantasy pieces dedicated to Liszt"]}, "182": {"question": "Who? ", "correct": "Yes", "incorrect": ["Maybe", "Them", "Same"]}, "183": {"question": "Who composed 'Coloured Leaves'?", "correct": "Schumann", "incorrect": ["Chopin", "Debussy", "Beethoven"]}, "184": {"question": "Who composed the Fantasiestücke called 'Why'?", "correct": "Schumann", "incorrect": ["Chopin", "Debussy", "Mozart"]}, "185": {"question": "Which composer was a cheeky bugger?", "correct": "Schumann, for playing a slightly disguised form of a fragment of 'Marseillaise', a piece banned in Vienna", "incorrect": ["Beethoven, for composing the Amongus imposter theme", "Debussy, for composing Claire de Lune", "Tchaikovsky, for referencing 'La Marseillaise' in the 1812 Overture"]}, "186": {"question": "For how many hands were Schumann's piano duets composed?", "correct": "4", "incorrect": ["2", "3", "6"]}, "187": {"question": "What period of composition does Chopin represent?", "correct": "Romantic", "incorrect": ["Baroque", "Classical", "Impressionist"]}, "188": {"question": "What period of composition does Schumann represent?", "correct": "Romantic", "incorrect": ["Baroque", "Classical", "Impressionist"]}, "189": {"question": "What period of composition does Debussy represent?", "correct": "Impressionist", "incorrect": ["Baroque", "Classical", "Romantic"]}, "190": {"question": "Which of the following clefs is used by the Bassoon?", "correct": "Bass", "incorrect": ["Treble", "Percussion", "Alto"]}, "191": {"question": "Which of the following clefs is used by the Bassoon?", "correct": "Tenor", "incorrect": ["Treble", "Percussion", "Alto"]}, "192": {"question": "Which of the following clefs is used by the Clarinet?", "correct": "Treble", "incorrect": ["Bass", "Tenor", "Alto"]}, "193": {"question": "What (written) note represents the bottom of the range of the Bassoon?", "correct": "B flat", "incorrect": ["E flat", "C", "G"]}, "194": {"question": "What (written) note represents the top of the range of the Bassoon?", "correct": "G", "incorrect": ["B flat", "C", "E flat"]}, "195": {"question": "What (written) note represents the bottom of the range of the Clarinet?", "correct": "E", "incorrect": ["C", "H", "E flat"]}, "196": {"question": "What (written) note represents the top of the range of the Clarinet?", "correct": "C", "incorrect": ["E flat", "B flat", "G"]}, "197": {"question": "What (written) note represents the bottom of the range of the Flute?", "correct": "C", "incorrect": ["D", "E", "B flat"]}, "198": {"question": "What (written) note represents the top of the range of the Flute?", "correct": "D", "incorrect": ["C", "E", "B flat"]}, "199": {"question": "What (written) note represents the bottom of the range of the Oboe?", "correct": "B flat", "incorrect": ["A", "C", "F"]}, "200": {"question": "What (written) note represents the top of the range of the Oboe?", "correct": "A", "incorrect": ["B flat", "E", "G"]}, "201": {"question": "Which type of piece was prominent within Chopin's compositional oeuvre (body of work)?", "correct": "Etude", "incorrect": ["Symphony", "Chamber", "Impromptu"]}, "202": {"question": "Which type of piece was prominent within Schumann's compositional oeuvre (body of work)?", "correct": "Symphony", "incorrect": ["Etude", "Impromptu", "Sonata"]}, "203": {"question": "Which type of piece was prominent within Debussy's compositional oeuvre (body of work)?", "correct": "Suite", "incorrect": ["Etude", "Sonata", "Symphony"]}, "204": {"question": "How is music written for Clarinet in A sounded?", "correct": "3 semitones lower", "incorrect": ["3 semitones higher", "2 tones lower", "2 tones higher"]}, "205": {"question": "Which of the following types of pieces does not form a substantial part of Chopin's composition:", "correct": "Symphony", "incorrect": ["Etude", "Impromptu", "Nocturne"]}, "206": {"question": "Which of the following types of pieces does not form a substantial part of Debussy's composition:", "correct": "Nocturne", "incorrect": ["Opera", "Sonata", "Clair de Lune"]}, "207": {"question": "Which of the following types of pieces does not form a substantial part of Schumann's composition:", "correct": "Fugue", "incorrect": ["Lieder", "Orchestral music", "Chamber"]}, "208": {"question": "Name a characteristic of Chopin's compositional style.", "correct": "Dissonance", "incorrect": ["12-tone serialism", "Minimalism", "Vocoding"]}, "209": {"question": "Name a characteristic of Debussy's compositional style.", "correct": "Non-traditional scales and tonal structures", "incorrect": ["Monophony", "Alliteration", "Alberti bass"]}, "210": {"question": "Name a characteristic of Schumann's compositional style.", "correct": "Strong rhythmic patterns", "incorrect": ["Dissonance", "Minimalism", "Basso ostinato"]}, "211": {"question": "What is an auxiliary instrument?", "correct": "A 'non-standard' version of the common members of an instrumental family", "incorrect": ["A supporting instrument in an ensemble", "An instrument made out of wood", "All of the above"]}, "212": {"question": "Which of the following is not typically found in an orchestra?", "correct": "The Contrabass Clarinet", "incorrect": ["The Bass Clarinet", "The Bb Clarinet", "The Flute"]}, "213": {"question": "Which of the following composers was not from the Romantic era?", "correct": "Debussy", "incorrect": ["Chopin", "Schumann", "Liszt"]}, "214": {"question": "Which of the following composers was not from the Impressionist era?", "correct": "Chopin", "incorrect": ["Debussy", "Ravel", "Verdi"]}, "215": {"question": "Which of the following composers was from the Impressionist era?", "correct": "Debussy", "incorrect": ["Chopin", "Schumann", "Liszt"]}, "216": {"question": "Who wrote 21 nocturnes?", "correct": "Chopin", "incorrect": ["Debussy", "Bach", "Joe Biden"]}}